

Arman Oganisian

PhD Candidate

Last Updated: April 2019

Philadelphia, PA, USA

github.com/stablemarkets stablemarkets.netlify.com

aoganisi@upenn.edu

About me ———

I am a biostatistics PhD Candidate at the University of Pennsylvania and an Associate Fellow at the Leonard Davis Institute for Health Economics. My research centers around developing flexible Bayesian models for solving various causal inference problems arising in health economics.

Research ———

- · Dirichlet process mixtures
- · Time-varying confounding
- Medical cost/cost-effectiveness
- Censored/incomplete costs.

Skills — Python Linux Git, Git Hub C++,Rcpp ₽T_FX

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

R

Education

2016- Pres. PhD, Biostatistics Philadelphia, PA

University of Pennsylvania

Advisors: Dr. Jason A. Roy and Dr. Nandita Mitra.

2016-2018 MS, Biostatistics Philadelphia, PA

University of Pennsylvania

Thesis: Joint Bayesian Hierarchical Model for Healthcare Utilization.

2009-2013 BA, Quantitative Economics Providence, RI

Providence College

summa cum laude; Mathematics minor;

Industry Experience

2013-2016 Senior Analyst

Analysis Group

Boston, MA

Worked in the health economics and outcome research (HEOR) practice. Conducted statistical analyses for large pharmaceutical companies - wrote analysis plans, supervised analysts coding analyses, lead client calls, drafted abstracts and manuscripts.

2012-2012 Equity Derivatives Analyst

New York, NY

Jefferies & Co.

Summer internship at an equity trading floor. Built statistical models predicting probability of mergers and spin-offs.

Professional Appointments

2017-Pres. Associate Fellow, Leonard Davis Institute of Health Economics.

Methodology Publications

2019 ChiRP: R Package for Chinese Restaurant Process Mixtures for Regres-

sion and Clustering.

Arman Oganisian. Journal of Open Source Software.

2018 A Bayesian latent class approach for EHR-based phenotyping.

> Rebecca A. Hubbard, Jing Huang, Joanna Harton, Arman Oganisian, Grace Choi, Levon Utidjian, Ihuoma Eneli, L. Charles Bailey, Yong

Chen. Statistics in Medicine.

Applied Publications

2019 Racial/Ethnic Variation in Use of Ambulatory and Emergency Care for

Atopic Dermatitis Among U.S. Children.

Joy Wan, Arman Oganisian (co-first), Andrew Spieker, Ole Hoffstad, Nandita Mitra, David Margolis, Junko Takeshita. Journal of Investiga-

tive Dermatology.

2019 Development of a Classifier to Identify Patients With Probable Lennox-Gastaut Syndrome in Health Insurance Claims Databases via Random

Forests.

F. Vekeman, J. E. PiÃśa-Garza, W. Y. Cheng, E. Tuttle, P. GiguÃÍre-Duval, Arman Oganisian, J. Damron, M. S. Duh, V. Shen, T. B. Saurer, G. D. Montouris, J. Isojarvi. *Current Medical Research and Opinion*.

2018 Impact of industry payments on prescribing patterns for tumor necrosis factor inhibitors among Medicare beneficiaries.

Partik Singh, Howard Forman, Adewole S. Adamson, Arash Mostaghimi, Alexis R. Ogdie, Arman Oganisian, John S. Barbieri. Jour-

nal of General Internal Medicine.



Arman Oganisian

PhD Candidate

(H)

Last Updated: April 2019



Philadelphia, PA, USA



github.com/stablemarkets



stablemarkets.netlify.com



aoganisi@upenn.edu

About me ——

I am a biostatistics PhD Candidate at the University of Pennsylvania and an Associate Fellow at the Leonard Davis Institute for Health Economics. My research centers around developing flexible Bayesian models for solving various causal inference problems arising in health economics.

Research -

C++,Rcpp

₽T_FX

R

- · Dirichlet process mixtures
- · Time-varying confounding
- Medical cost/cost-effectiveness
- Censored/incomplete costs.

Python Linux Git,GitHub

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

Invited Talks

2020 An all-in-one Bayesian nonparametric model for medical cost predic-

tion, clustering, and causal estimation

International Conference on Health Policy Statistics. San Diego, CA.

2019 Bayesian nonparametric model for zero-inflated outcomes

Joint Statistical Meetings. Denver, CO.

Contributed Talks

2018 A Bayesian Nonparametric Method for Zero-Inflated Data with Appli-

cations to Medical Costs

Joint Statistical Meetings. Vancouver, BC, Canada.

2017 A Parametric Bayesian Approach to Estimating Causal Treatment Ef-

fect on Medical Costs.

Joint Statistical Meetings. Baltimore, MD.

Teaching

2019 Guest Lecture for BSTA670 Programming and Computation for

Biomedical Data Science: Bayesian Computation: MCMC Sampling,

Integration, and Approximation Methods.

2018 JSM short course: Introduction to Bayesian Nonparametric Meth-

ods for Causal Inference. Interactive Dirichlet Process tutorial with

R Shiny. https://stablemarkets.shinyapps.io/dpmixapp/

2018 Guest Lecture for BSTA622 Inference II: Bayesian Motivations of Pe-

nalized Regression and the EM Algorithm.

2018 Instructor, Causal Inference Summer Institute. Taught computing

session on instrumental variables and 2SLS in R.

2018 TA, HPR604 Introduction to Statistics for Health Policy.

2018 TA, BSTA660 Design of Observational Studies.

[Professional Activities]

2017-Pres. Student Representative, UPenn biostatistics MS/PhD curriculum

committee.

2019 Chair, Bayesian Approaches to High Dimensional Data. Contributed

Papers. Eastern North American Region. Philadelphia, PA.

2017 Chair, New Ideas in Causal Inference. Poster Session. Eastern North

American Region. Washington, D.C.